Finding Aid for Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project Records, 1947-2003
Bentley Historical Library
- Research, 1948-2003
  - Research Grants, Nos. 1-816, 1948-1996
    - #801-865
      - Neutron Radioscopy Imaging of Non-Aqueous Phase Liquid (NAPL) Mobilization and Solubilization during Surfactant Flushing, K. Pennell, [823] (Box 53)
      - Identification of Mineralocorticoid Response Genes, A. Killeen, [824] (Box 53)
      - The Molecular Basis of Thyroid Hormone Action in Neural Development, R. Denver, [825] (Box 53)
      - Regulation of Sexual Identity in C. elegans Germ Cells, R. Ellis, [826] (Box 53)
      - Differential Gene Expression in Adrenal Cortical Neoplasms, T. Giodano, [827] (Box 53)
      - Development of a Biological Model for Telomere Shortening, J. Langmore, [828] (Box 53)
      - Non-Invasive Quantification of Pancreas Exocrine Function Using Positron Emission Teomography, P. Shreve, [829] (Box 53)
      - Radiation-Enhanced Diffusion in Radioactive Waste Storage Materials, M. Atzmon, [830] (Box 53)
      - Enhanced Neutrino Interactions in Transient Microwave Passage, Y. Tomozawa, [831] (Box 53)
      - Monitoring the Aztec Salt Trade Through High Precision Trace-Element Characterization of Ceramic Salt Ware, J. Parsons and L. Minc, [832] (Box 53)
      - The Regulation of Angiogenesis in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer, D. Arenberg, [833] (Box 53)
      - Functional Analysis of a Disulfide Catalyst, J. Bardwell, [834] (Box 53)
      - Molecular Mechanisms of Insulin-Like Growth Factor-I Action in Vascular Smooth Muscle Cells, C. Duan, [835] (Box 53)
      - Role of CDK-Activating Kinase (CAK) in the Induction of p53, M. Ljungman, [836] (Box 53)
      - Covalent Alteration of Penile Nitric Oxide Synthase, Y. Osawa, [837] (Box 53)
      - Identification of Molecular Components Involved in Radiation-Induced Programmed Cell Death, A. Rehemtulla, [838] (Box 53)
      - Proton Implantation of Power Silicon MOSFETs for Superior Body Diode Recovery, V. Godbold, [839] (Box 53)
      - Deutrerated Liquid Scintillator as a Fast Neutron Detector, J. Janecke, [840] (Box 53)
      - Women Scientists and the Internationalization of Peaceful Nuclear Technologies: Technical Training, Policy, and Gender in The Early "Atoms for Peace" Era L. Calkins, 1948-1965; [841] (Box 53)
      - Economics of Low-Level Radioactive Waste Disposal, R. Porter, [842] (Box 53)
      - Isolation, Characterization and Functional Analysis of the Xenopus msx-2 gene, S. Gong, [843] (Box 53)
      - High Resolution Genetic Analysis of the Mouse Deafness Mutant "Spinner," D. Kohrmann, [844] (Box 53)
      - Characterization of the Functional Defect In Wilson's Disease, R. Moseley, [845] (Box 53)
      - Structure Determination of the Second Transmembrane Peptide Fragment of Human a2-GABAA Receptor Using Solid-State NMR Spectroscopy, A. Ramamoorthy, [846] (Box 53)
      - The Role of Daxx in ?-Radiation-Induced Apoptosis, S. Wu, [847] (Box 53)
      - Teaching Simulations for Topics in Nuclear Medicine, F. Becchetti, [848] (Box 53)
      - Transmission Electron Microscopy Study of Radiation Effects of Actinide Containing Minerals and Neutron Irradiated Ceramic Materials, L. Wang, [849] (Box 53)
      - Analysis of Function of Transcription Enhancer Factor One in Heart Formation, Z. Chen, [850] (Box 53)
      - Analysis of Tissue-Specific Intercellular Signaling in Drosophila, K. Cadigan, [851] (Box 53)
      - Protein Interactions Controlling ER to Golgi Vesicle Transport, J. Hay, [853] (Box 53)
      - Mapping a Gene Responsible for Dominant Nonsyndromic Hearing Impairment, M. Lesperance, [854] (Box 53)
      - Identification of Novel Components of the Brassinosteroid Signaling Pathway, J. Li, [855] (Box 53)
      - Cell-Cell Interactions Mediated by Alpha(1,2)Fucosylated Oligosaccharides, S. Domino, [856] (Box 53)
      - Determining Reproductive Success in Endangered Freshwater Mussels with DNA Fingerprinting, D. O'Foighil, [857] (Box 53)
      - Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Inhibitors for Imaging Tumor Biochemistry Using Positron Emission Tomography, S. Snyder, [858] (Box 53)
      - Role of the Camguk Adapter Protein in EAG Channel Modulation and in Behavior, G. Wilson, [859] (Box 53)
      - The Composition Problem in Prompt Gamma Neutron Activation Analysis of Large Samples, J. Holloway, [860] (Box 53)
      - Archaeological Ceramic Source and Production Analysis in Colonial New Mexico Using Ethnographic Consultation and INAA, R. Ford, [861] (Box 53)
      - Neuroendocrine Effects of Repeated Social Defeat in Rats, S. Bhatnagar, [862] (Box 53)
      - Role of Acute Physical Inactivity and Diet on Lipid Metabolism, J. Horowitz, [863] (Box 53)
      - Dental Pulp-Derived Neurotrophic Factors, C. Nosrat, [864] (Box 53)
      - Research Investigation into the Use of Nuclear Gauges for the Determination of Density of Mine Tailings, R. Green, [865] (Box 53)
    - Compendium of Faculty Research Grants
      - Volume 1 (Box 54)
- Audio Material
  The Audio Material series, 1961 and undated (0.5 linear ft.), include recordings of the first two Dewey F. Fagerburg Memorial Lectures given by Donald Glaser and Robert Oppenheimer; director William Kerr interviews with Voice of America and WUOM; and ten "Age of the Atom" radio programs.
  - Age of the Atom Programs 1 through 5, [Undated]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-1-1]; (Broadcast on WJR radio, discusses the Michigan Memorial Phoenix, it's facilities, and work.)
  - Age of the Atom Programs 6 through 10, [Undated]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-2-1]; (WJR radio program interview discussing the legal issues, medical uses, and other practical uses of nuclear energy.)
  - Donald A. Glaser Lectures Lecture I, 1961 January 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-3-1]; (Glaser lectures on the basics of nuclear physics and his bubble chamber after receiving the Nobel Prize.)
  - Donald A. Glaser Lectures Lecture II, 1961 January 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-4-1]; (Glaser lectures on the basics of nuclear physics and his bubble chamber after receiving the Nobel Prize.)
  - William Kerr, Curt Knight; Interviews Voice of America, 1961 April 22; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-5-1]; (William Kerr discusses the Memorial Phoenix's efforts to develop nuclear energy in other countries.)
  - William Kerr Interview with WUOM on Campus News, 1961 April 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-6-1]; (William Kerr discusses the Memorial Phoenix's efforts to develop nuclear energy in other countries and international students studying at the Phoenix Project.)
  - J. Robert Oppenheimer Lecture I, 1962; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-7-1]; (Oppenheimer discusses nuclear physics at a lecture at the University of Michigan.)
  - J. Robert Oppenheimer Lecture II, 1962; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-8-1]; (Oppenheimer discusses nuclear physics at a lecture at the University of Michigan.)
  - J. Robert Oppenheimer / Dewey Fagerburg Memorial Lecture, 1962; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 52)
    - [Part 1], [87278-SR-9-1]; (Oppenheimer discusses nuclear physics at a lecture at the University of Michigan. This speech is identical to 87278-SR-7 and 87278-SR-8.)
Related Material
Publications produced by the Phoenix Project are cataloged and described separately under the title Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project Publications, 1949-ongoing.
The University of Michigan Media Resources Center record group includes film footage of the dedication of the Ford Nuclear Reactor and miscellaneous footage of the research activities at the reactor.